Doru-Petru Barbu

curriculum vitae

I'm a seasoned programmer with more than a decade of comprehensive experience in all facets of the software development lifecycle. From the initial analysis to the post-release support phase, I have contributed to the success of projects delivered to more than 20 customers across 14 European and Asian countries, from Portugal to Singapore.

contact details

Email db@0db.ro

Github https://github.com/fragilematter

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/doru-barbu

work experience

IT Consultant and Software Developer

2021-11 - present

Custom Logisoft Labs SRL

Provided specialized services such as disaster recovery, server configuration and troubleshooting. Designed stop-gap solutions (e.g. backporting software to obsolete server platforms) to facilitate infrastructure upgrades.

Facilitated support and migration for unmaintained closed source software by documenting flows through protocol analysis and reverse engineering. Developed extensions and ancillary tools/services using PHP, Laravel and JavaScript.

Senior Software Developer

2016-12 - 2024-03

Bell Gateway SRL

Took over and led the development of a logistics suite for vehicle transportation, stocking and maintenance, developed using PHP and MSSQL. Led the effort to rebase the project from a custom legacy framework to Laravel with no downtime, from the initial concept to the development roadmap and the implementation; designed and documented new REST APIs replacing the existing SOAP implementation.

Participated in analysis, deployment and post-release support for projects using Jira, Microsoft Teams, FreeScout. Performed configuration and server administration for SaaS customers as well as on premise deployments.

Software Developer

2012-12 - 2016-12

Gateway Software SRL

Participated in the development of a large scale SCM system designed for passenger vehicle configuration, ordering, tracking, and sale to dealers. Developed desktop and full stack solutions using .Net WinForms + DevExpress, ASP.NET, MSSQL, Crystal Reports.

Participated in requirement analysis and design, extended the integration with third party solutions, including specific communication interfaces for ANSI Cobol 74/85 files. Wrote specifications, technical documentation, quotes and planned the development of software solutions using Lotus Notes and Jira. Maintained legacy Visual Basic 6 and ASP software solutions.

Software Developer

2010-12 - 2012-12

Expert Software Company SRL

Participated in the development, continuous updating, deployment and support of a fully featured accounting software suite developed using Microsoft Visual FoxPro and Microsoft SQL/MySql. Led the analysis and development effort for a logistics solution targeted at TL and LTL shipping, featuring load-unload planning, weight/volume/floor space calculation, automated SMS notifications and refueling data import.

Developed custom made-to-order software, ranging from ERP solutions, timesheet tracking integrated with access control, stock management systems integrated with industrial weighing scales.

Linux News Editor in English

2009-07 - 2010-01

SoftNews NET (Softpedia)

Tracked events in the IT/Linux area of interest and wrote articles, reviews and tutorials on open source software, accessible on my Editor Profile and Review Archive. Maintained and expanded a database of open source software, including download links, changelogs, short descriptions and screenshots. Translated news pieces from English to Romanian - Softpedia Forum Translations Archive.

IT Tech 2007-09 – 2008-09

"Gheorghe Lazăr" National College

Provided hardware maintenance and troubleshooting, networking, software solution support. Performed setup of video and sound infrastructure for events.

education

BSc. Informatics

2007 - 2010

Spiru Haret University

Courses regarding statistical and numerical analysis, computer architecture, networking, sequential and programmable automata, software engineering and high level programming.

skills

Languages Bash, C/C++, C#/VB.net, CSS3, HTML5, Java, Lua, PHP, SQL, Javascript

Instruments DevExpress, Github/Gitlab, Kendo UI, Laravel

Abilities Software Development, Database Design, System Administration, API De-

sign, Security Best Practices

references

Available upon request